Register to The David Stanley Smith Papers
Yale University Library
- Music, I
  - Solo instrument / voice with orchestra, I.B
    - [Fête galante, flute, orchestra, op. 48 (Revision)] 1930 Aug 27 (Box 15)
      - [Fête galante, flute, orchestra, op. 48 (Revision)] 1930 Aug 27, 3 scores (37, 39, 39 p.); 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 100)
        Two holographs signed, in ink, bound; one holograph signed, in pencil.
        Feb. 2, 1921 - New Haven. Revised August 27, 1930 - Yelping Hill.
        Manuscript sheet with dates of performances of 2 versions laid in with 2nd score.
      - [Fête galante, flute, orchestra, op. 48 (Revision)] 1930 Aug 27, 42 parts; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 101-102)
    - [Prelude, choral and fugue, organ, orchestra, op. 10] [1903], 1 score (33 p.); 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 103)
      Thesis for Mus. B. 1903 composed Paris -- title page. Performed at Yale Commencement 1903, which was probably the first public use of the Woolsey Hall organ, then still unfinished.
    - [Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81] 1939 Aug 24
      - [Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81] 1939 Aug 24, 1 score (43 p.); 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 104)
      - [Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81] 1939 Aug 24, 1 score (34 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 104)
      - [Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81] 1939 Aug 24, 1 score (32 p.); 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 105)
      - [Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81] 1939 Aug 24, 4 string parts; 32 cm. (Box 15, Folder 106)
        Holographs signed, in ink, some transparencies.
      - [Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81] 1939 Aug 24, 53 parts; 33-35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 107)
        Holographs signed, in ink and facsimiles of holograph.
      - [Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81] 1939 Aug 24, 41 parts; 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 108)
        Manuscript in ink, and facsimiles of holograph.
    - [Rondo appassionato, violin, orchestra, op. 73] 1935 Aug-Sep
      - [Rondo appassionato, violin, orchestra, op. 73] 1935 Aug-Sep, 1 score (52, [1] p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 15)
      - [Rondo appassionato, violin, orchestra, op. 73] 1935 Aug-Sep, 1 score (58 p.); 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 109)
        At head of title: To Jacques Gordon.
      - [Rondo appassionato, violin, orchestra, op. 73] 1935 Aug-Sep, 1 score ([57?] p.); 35 cm. (Box 15, Folder 110)
        Incomplete: pp. 51-57 only.
      - [Rondo appassionato, violin, orchestra, op. 73] 1935 Aug-Sep, 50 parts; 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 111)
        Holographs, other manuscripts, and facsimiles of holographs.
    - [Rondo appassionato, violin, orchestra, op. 73 (Sketches)], 6 p. of music; 42 cm. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Band, I.C
    - Adagietto, band.
      See: Compositions, band, op. 101.
    - Badinage, band.
    - [Compositions, band, op. 101] (Box 16)
      - Two compositions for concert band., 1 score (17, 23 p.); 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 112)
        Contents: I. Adagietto -- II. Badinage.
      - Two compositions for concert band., 47 parts; 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 113)
        Holographs signed, in ink and other manuscripts.
      - Two pieces for concert band 1949 Apr-Jun, 1 condensed score (4, 5 p.); 32 cm. (Box 16, Folder 114)
      - [Two pieces for concert band] 1949 May 18, 1 condensed score (3 p.); 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 115)
        Contains: Adagietto
        Holograph signed in ink with orchestration markings in pencil.
      - Scherzo for band 1949 Mar 16, 1 condensed score (4 p.); 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 115)
    - Pieces, band, op. 101.
  - Chamber music, I.D
    - Ballade, violoncello, piano.
      See: Poems, violoncello, piano, op. 97 [bis]
    - La belle dame, violin, piano.
      See: Unrelated pieces, violin, piano, op. 96 [bis]
    - Berceuse, violin, piano.
    - [Caprice, bassoon, piano, op. 50 [bis]] (Box 16, Folder 116)
      - 1924 Jan 15, 1 score ([3] p.) + 1 part; 35 cm.
        Holograph signed (score in pencil, part in ink.)
      - [Caprice, bassoon, piano, op. 50 [bis]], 1 score (7 p.) 1 part; 30 cm.
        (Selected compositions for bassoon with piano accompaniment, W661)
        Two copies.
    - [Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 69, F; arr.] Concerto in F.
      - [Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 69, F; arr.] Concerto in F., 1 score (18 p.); 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 117)
        Accompaniment arranged for piano.
      - [Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 69, F; arr.] Concerto in F., 1 score (18 p.) + 2 parts; 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 118)
        Includes solo violin and violin parts.
    - [Concerto, violin, orchestra, op. 86, G; arr.] 1942 Jan-Jun, 1 score (33 p.) + 2 parts; 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 119)
      Includes two copies of the violin part.
    - [Fête galante, flute, orchestra, op. 48; arr.] Fête galante (after Watteau): for flute and orchestra. 1921, 1 score (11 p.) + 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 120)
      "The original version in D flat major (1921); orchestral accompaniment arranged for piano - p. 1.
    - [Fête galante, flute, orchestra, op. 48 (Revision); arr.] Fête galante: arrangement for flute and piano. 1930 Sep 2
      - [Fête galante, flute, orchestra, op. 48 (Revision); arr.] Fête galante: arrangement for flute and piano. 1930 Sep 2, 1 score (11 p.) + 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 121)
        At head of title: To Georges Barrère.
      - [Fête galante, flute, orchestra, op. 48 (Revision); arr.] Fête galante: arrangement for flute and piano. 1930 Sep 2, 1 score (9 sheets) + 1 part (4 sheets); 31-34 cm. (Box 16, Folder 122)
        Holograph transparencies signed, in ink for reproduction by the National Blue Print Co., N.Y.
      - [Fête galante, flute, orchestra, op. 48 (Revision); arr.] Fête galante: arrangement for flute and piano. 1930 Sep 2, 1 score + 1 part, bound; 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 123)
        Photocopies of holograph.
    - [Lyric poems, violin, piano, op. 64] 1931 Sep 10
      - [Lyric poems, violin, piano, op. 64] 1931 Sep 10, 1 score (23 p.) + 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 124)
        Contents: 1. Adagio -- 2. Adagio - Allegretto capricioso -- 3. Allegro.
      - [Lyric poems, violin, piano, op. 64] 1931 Sep 10, 1 score (23 p.) + 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 125)
    - Oracle, violoncello, piano.
    - Pieces, violin, piano, op. 96.
    - Poem in three parts.
      See: Quartet, strings, op. 90, A.
    - [Poems, violoncello, piano, op. 97 [bis]] Three poems for violoncello and piano. 1947 Feb 18-26
      - [Poems, violoncello, piano, op. 97 [bis]] Three poems for violoncello and piano. 1947 Feb 18-26, 1 score (6, 6, 7 p.) + 3 parts; 32 cm. (Box 16, Folder 126)
        Contents: Ballade -- Promenade -- Oracle.
      - [Poems, violoncello, piano, op. 97 [bis]] Three poems for violoncello and piano. 1947 Feb 18-26, 1 score (6, 6, 7 p.); 32 cm. (Box 16, Folder 127)
      - [Poems, violoncello, piano, op. 97 [bis]] Three poems for violoncello and piano. 1947 Feb 18-26, [1], 6, 6, 7 sheets of music; 32 cm. (Box 16, Folder 127)
        Photocopy of above manuscript.
    - [Praeludium triumphale, violin, piano [op. 75 bis]] 1936 Jul 16, 1 score (12 p.) + 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 16, Folder 128)
    - [Praeludium triumphale, violin, piano [op. 75 bis] (Sketches)] Praeludium. 1936 Jul 11, 1 score (5 p.); 32 cm. (Box 16, Folder 129)
      [2] p. of sketches at end.
    - Promenade, violoncello, piano.
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 2, C minor] [1899], 1 score (46 p.); 36 cm. (Box 16, Folder 130)
      "Composed 1899" -- card.
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 2, C minor (Sketches)] (Box 16, Folder 130)
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 2, C minor (Sketches)], 3 p. of music; 35 cm.
        Holograph in ink.
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 2, C minor (Sketches)], [8] p. of music; 34 cm.
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 19, E minor] [1906] (Box 16, Folder 131)
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 19, E minor] [1906], 1 score (68 p.); 34 cm.
        Holograph signed, in ink and blue pencil.
        "Composed 1906" -- card.
        At head of title: To Dr. Franz Kneisel.
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 19, E minor] [1906], 4 parts; 35 cm.
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 37, A major], 1 score (54 p.); 32 cm. (Box 17, Folder 132)
      Note by David Stanley Smith re chronology of this work on cover.
      See also: Quartet, strings, op. 90, A.
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 46, C minor] (Box 17, Folder 133)
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 46, C minor], 1 score (19 p.) + 4 parts; 27-31 cm.
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 46, C minor], 4 parts; 31 cm.
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 57, E flat] 1927 Jun 21
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 57, E flat] 1927 Jun 21, 1 score (49 p.); 35 cm. (Box 17, Folder 134)
        Dedicated to Mrs. Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge in celebration of her receiving the honorary degree of Master of Arts from Yale University, 1927.
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 57, E flat] 1927 Jun 21, 4 parts, bound; 36 cm. (Box 17, Folder 134)
        Photocopy (positive) of the composer's holograph.
        Two copies, one with pencil markings.
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 57, E flat] 1927 Jun 21, 1 score (50 p.), bound; 28 cm. (Box 17, Folder 134)
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 57, E flat] 1927 Jun 21, 1 score (36 p.) + 4 parts; 26-31 cm. (Box 17, Folder 135)
        Two copies of parts.
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 62, D major] [1931]
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 62, D major] [1931], 4 parts; 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 136)
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 62, D major] [1931], 1 score (49 leaves); 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 137)
        "Composed, 1931" -- card.
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 62, D major (Sketches)] 1931 Jan 28, 26, [5], 13, [2] p. of music, bound; 31 cm. (Box 18, Folder 138)
      Contains sketches for an untitled organ work and "1929."
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 71, C] 1934-1935
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 71, C] 1934-1935, 1 score (51 p.); 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 139)
        New ending dated 1935 Nov 12 (p. 51.)
        At head of title; To Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge.
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 71, C] 1934-1935, 1 score (50 p.)+ 4 parts; 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 140)
        "The music for the published version was afterwards greatly revised." -- title page.
      - String quartet no. 6. -- New York: Carl Fischer, Inc., 1937., 1 score (47 p.) + 4 parts; 27-31 cm. (Box 18, Folder 141)
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 71, C (Sketches)], 24 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 142)
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 74, D minor] 1936 Jan 12 (Box 18, Folder 143)
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 74, D minor] 1936 Jan 12, 1 score (29 p.); 35 cm.
        "In memory of J. Haydn" -- at end.
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 74, D minor] 1936 Jan 12, 4 parts; 33 cm.
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 74, D minor] 1936 Jan 12, 1 score (31 leaves); 35 cm.
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 77, A] Quartet no. 8. 1936 Apr 4
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 77, A] Quartet no. 8. 1936 Apr 4, 1 score (41 p.) + 4 parts; 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 144)
        "Composed 1936" -- card.
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 77, A] Quartet no. 8. 1936 Apr 4, 1 score (30 [i.e. 3 p.] + 4 parts; 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 145)
        "Composed 1936" -- card; "copied 6/14/55."
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 77, A] Quartet no. 8. 1936 Apr 4, 1 score (51 p.); 32-35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 146)
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 80, B flat] Quartet No. 9 in B flat. 1938 Nov 26
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 80, B flat] Quartet No. 9 in B flat. 1938 Nov 26, 1 score (45 p.); 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 147)
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 80, B flat] Quartet No. 9 in B flat. 1938 Nov 26, 4 parts; 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 147)
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 80, B flat] Quartet No. 9 in B flat. 1938 Nov 26, 1 score (49 sheets); 35 cm. (Box 18, Folder 148)
        Photocopy of composer's holograph.
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 90, A] Poem in three parts. 1939 Jul 12
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 90, A] Poem in three parts. 1939 Jul 12, 1 score (36 p.) + 4 parts; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 149)
        Note by David Stanley Smith on cover re the chronology of this work, 1945 May 25.
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 90, A] Poem in three parts. 1939 Jul 12, 1 score (34 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 150)
    - [Quartet, strings, op. 90, A] Quartet No. 10. 1944 Mar 3 (Box 19, Folder 151)
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 90, A] Quartet No. 10. 1944 Mar 3, 1 score (25 p.); 35 cm.
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 90, A] Quartet No. 10. 1944 Mar 3, 1 score (33 p.); 35 cm.
      - [Quartet, strings, op. 90, A] Quartet No. 10. 1944 Mar 3, 1 score (24 p.); 35 cm.
    - Quartet, strings, no. 6, C.
      See: Quartet, strings, op. 71, C.
    - [Quartets, string (Sketches)], Loose sheets ([13] p. of music); 25-35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 152)
      Holographs in pencil.
      Two sheets are labeled Quartet no, 2.
    - [Quintet, piano, strings, op. 56, E flat] 1928
      - [Quintet, piano, strings, op. 56, E flat] 1928, 1 score (76 p.) + 4 parts; 31 cm. (Box 19, Folder 153)
        Two copies of score, one bound, and two copies of each part.
      - 1926 Aug 14, 1 score (64 p.) + 4 parts; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 154)
        Holograph signed, in pencil (parts in ink.)
    - [Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81; arr.] Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81: Poem for violin and orchestra. 1939 Aug 31
      - [Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81; arr.] Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81: Poem for violin and orchestra. 1939 Aug 31, 1 score (10 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 155)
      - [Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81; arr.] Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81: Poem for violin and orchestra. 1939 Aug 31, 1 score (10 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 155)
      - [Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81; arr.] Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81: Poem for violin and orchestra. 1939 Aug 31, 1 score (12 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 156)
        Photocopy of the composer's holograph, with holograph (in ink) title page.
      - [Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81; arr.] Requiem, violin, orchestra, op. 81: Poem for violin and orchestra. 1939 Aug 31, 1 score (12 sheets); 34 cm. (Box 19, Folder 156)
        Sheet with sketches of a few measures laid in.
        Added 1982 Jul.
    - Romanza for violin.
    - [Rondo appassionato, violin, orchestra, op. 73; arr.], 1 score (16 p.) + 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 157)
    - [Scenes from tragedy, violin, piano, op. 67], 1 score (19 p.) + 1 part; 32 cm. (Box 19, Folder 158)
      Facsimile of the composer's holograph.
      Contents: Medea -- Lament for Antigone -- Death of Oedipus.
      Three copies, two with pencil corrections, one part wanting.
    - [Sextet, strings, op. 63, D minor], 1 score (70 p.); 35 cm. (Box 19, Folder 159)
    - [Sextet, strings, op. 63, D minor (Sketches)] 1931 Jun-Jul, 26, 6 p. of music, bound; 32 cm. (Box 19, Folder 160)
      Also contains sketch for Sinfonietta.
    - Small sonata, 2 violins, op. 91.
      See: Sonata, 2 violins, op. 91.
    - [Sonata, clarinet, piano, op. 84] 1941-1944, 1 score (20, [1] p.) + 1 part; 32-35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 161)
    - [Sonata, oboe, piano, op. 43] Sonata pastorale. -- New York: G. Schirmer, 1926., 1 score (37 p.) + 1 part; 30 cm. (Box 20, Folder 162)
      Three copies.
    - [Sonata, viola, piano, op. 72] 1934 Aug-Sep (Box 20, Folder 163)
      - [Sonata, viola, piano, op. 72] 1934 Aug-Sep, 1 score (24 p.); 35 cm.
      - [Sonata, viola, piano, op. 72] 1934 Aug-Sep, 1 score (11, [1] p.); 35 cm.
    - [Sonata, viola, piano, op. 72 (Sketches)] 1934 Aug 17, 8 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 164)
    - [Sonata, violin, piano, op. 51, A] 1924 Jan 1
      - [Sonata, violin, piano, op. 51, A] 1924 Jan 1, 1 score (49 p.) + 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 165)
        Holographs signed, in pencil, part in ink.
        Part incomplete: pp. 8 to end wanting.
      - [Sonata, violin, piano, op. 51, A] 1924 Jan 1, 1 score (63 p.) + 1 part; 31 cm. (Box 20, Folder 166)
    - [Sonata, violin, piano, op. 93, D] Second sonata in D for violin and piano 1945 Apr 15, 1 score (27 p.) + 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 167)
    - [Sonata, violin, piano, op. 96, D minor] 1946 Sep 23, 1 score (42 p.) + 1 part; 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 168)
    - [Sonata, violin, piano (Sketches)], [1] sheet of music; 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 169)
      Unidentified work for violin and piano.
    - [Sonata, 2 violins, op. 91] Small sonata: for two violins. 1944 Aug 19 (Box 20, Folder 170)
      - [Sonata, 2 violins, op. 91] Small sonata: for two violins. 1944 Aug 19, 1 score (11 p.) + 2 parts; 35 cm.
      - [Sonata, 2 violins, op. 91] Small sonata: for two violins. 1944 Aug 19, 1 score (8 p.); 35 cm.
    - [Sonata, violin, violoncello, op. 68] Sonata a Due Voci: [1933 - revised 1942] 1933-1942
      - [Sonata, violin, violoncello, op. 68] Sonata a Due Voci: [1933 - revised 1942] 1933-1942, 1 score (14 p.); 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 171)
        Note in pencil from David Stanley Smith to "Howard" laid in.
      - [Sonata, violin, violoncello, op. 68] Sonata a Due Voci: [1933 - revised 1942] 1933-1942, 1 score (14 p.); 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 171)
        "Correct version" -- cover.
      - [Sonata, violin, violoncello, op. 68] Sonata a Due Voci: [1933 - revised 1942] 1933-1942, 2 scores (14 p. each); 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 172)
        At head of title: Original version (not to be used.)
        One score labeled "Violin", the other "Violoncello."
    - [Sonata, violin, violoncello, op. 68 (Sketches)] 1933 Jan 17, 1 score (12 [i.e. 14] p.); 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 173)
      Holograph signed, in pencil.,
    - [Sonata, violoncello, piano, op. 59] New York: G. Schirmer (Inc.), 1929., 1 score (34 p.) + 1 part; 31 cm. (Box 20, Folder 174)
      Two copies, one bound.
    - Time: five-four, violin, piano.
    - [Tragic prelude, violin, piano, op. 41 [bis]] 1917, 1 score (18 p.) + 1 part; 34 cm. (Box 20, Folder 175)
    - Tragic prelude, violin, piano, op. 67.
      See: Scenes from tragedy, violin, piano, op. 67.
    - [Trio, piano, strings, op. 16, G major] 1905 Sep 9 (Box 20, Folder 176)
      - [Trio, piano, strings, op. 16, G major] 1905 Sep 9, 1 score (63 p.); 33 cm.
        "To the Adamowski Trio" -- cover.
      - [Trio, piano, strings, op. 16, G major] 1905 Sep 9, 1 score (62 p.) + 2 parts; 34 cm.
        Two pages added to supply material omitted at rehearsal letter "S."
    - [Trio, piano, strings, op. 44, C major] 1919 Jul-Aug, 1 score (69 p.) + 2 parts; 35 cm. (Box 20, Folder 177)
    - [Unrelated pieces, violin, piano, op. 96 [bis]] Three unrelated pieces: for violin with piano accompaniment. 1947 Jan 1 (Box 20, Folder 178)
      - [Unrelated pieces, violin, piano, op. 96 [bis]] Three unrelated pieces: for violin with piano accompaniment. 1947 Jan 1, 1 score (5, 7, 5 p.) + 3 parts; 32 cm.
        Contents: La belle dame -- Berceuse -- Time: five-four.
      - [Unrelated pieces, violin, piano, op. 96 [bis]] Three unrelated pieces: for violin with piano accompaniment. 1947 Jan 1, 1 score (5, 7, 5 p.); 32 cm.
      - [Unrelated pieces, violin, piano, op. 96 [bis]] Three unrelated pieces: for violin with piano accompaniment. 1947 Jan 1, 1 score (5, 7, 5 sheets); 36 cm.
  - Keyboard Works, I.E
    - "Alhambra" waltzes for piano.
    - Asahel march.
    - Boulevard two-step.
    - [Cathedral prelude, organ, orchestra, op. 54; arr.] (Box 21, Folder 179)
      - [Cathedral prelude, organ, orchestra, op. 54; arr.], 1 score (26 p.); 35 cm.
      - [Cathedral prelude, organ, orchestra, op. 54; arr.], 1 score (25, [1] p.), bound; 35 cm.
    - Charity ball two-step.
    - Clouds, piano.
      See: Compositions, piano, op. 87.
    - [Compositions, piano, op. 87] [1942-1943] (Box 21, Folder 180)
      - [Compositions, piano, op. 87] [1942-1943], 6, 3, 6, 3, 6 p. of music; 35 cm.
        Contents: 1. Prelude -- 2. Ianthe -- 3. Clouds -- 4. Nocturnes -- 5. Flight.
      - [Compositions, piano, op. 87] [1942-1943], 4, 3, 6, 4, 6 p. of music; 35 cm.
        Added to the papers, 1982 Apr.
    - [Compositions, piano, op. 87 (Sketches)] 1942 Aug 4-17, Various paginations of music; 35 cm. (Box 21, Folder 181)
      Holographs signed, in pencil.
    - [Credo, orchestra, op. 83; arr.] [1941]
      - [Credo, orchestra, op. 83; arr.] [1941], 1 condensed score (10 leaves); 34 cm. (Box 21, Folder 182)
        Arrangement for piano, 4 hands.
      - [Credo, orchestra, op. 83; arr.] [1941], 1 condensed score (10 p.), bound; 34 cm. (Box 21)
        Photocopy of above holograph.
        Four copies with holograph title pages.
    - [Danse fantastique] New York: G. Schirmer, 1906., 7 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 21, Folder 183)
      For piano.
    - La Débutante waltz.
    - [La Désespérée] La Désespérée: un portrait., [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 21, Folder 184)
    - [Dramatic fantasy, piano, op. 82] 1940 Jul-Nov (Box 21, Folder 185)
      - Poem in two parts: written in time of war., 19 p. of music; 35 cm.
        "Later Second sonata for pianoforte. Later Dramatic fantasy" -- cover.
      - Second-sonata: (freely designed), 32 p. of music; 35 cm.
      - Second sonata: [1941] 1940-1941, 30 p. of music; 35 cm.
      - Dramatic fantasy for piano., 24 p. of music; 35 cm.
    - [Dramatic fantasy, piano, op. 82 (Sketches)] Second sonata., [6] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 21, Folder 185)
    - [Evening harmonies, organ] 1903 Feb 5, [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 21, Folder 186)
    - [Evensong and choral] 1906 Dec 31, 8 p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 21, Folder 187)
      Holograph signed, in ink with pencil markings.
      For organ.
    - [Fantasia and five-voiced fugue], 14 p. [i.e. 12 p.] of music; 32 cm. (Box 21, Folder 188)
    - Flight, piano.
    - [Fugues, organ. Selections] 1896-1936, Various paginations; 32-35 cm. (Box 21, Folder 189)
      Most apparently composed as models for or during composition classes.
      Contents: Fugue -- Fugue for organ: theme by Prof. H.W. Parker -- Fugue in five voices for organ -- Fugue for organ: theme by Prof. H.W. Parker -- Fugue in three voices, or Fugue in g minor (6 copies) -- Fuga a tre voci, or Fuga C (3 copies) -- Fugato on a canto fermo of Cherubini (5 copies, 2 holograph.)
    - Gavotte.
    - [Ground bass and fugue, organ, op. 70, no. 1] (Box 21, Folder 190)
      - [Ground bass and fugue, organ, op. 70, no. 1], 12 p. of music; 35 cm.
        Also includes: Partita classica... op. 70, no. 2.
      - [Ground bass and fugue, organ, op. 70, no. 1], 12 p. of music; 35 cm.
        "To H. Frank Bozyan" -- p. 1.
    - [Humoresque] 1919 Apr 6, 4 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 21, Folder 191)
      Sheet with corrections laid in.
    - Ianthe, piano.
    - [Meeres-stille] 1909 Oct 18, [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 21, Folder 192)
    - [Meeres-stille (Sketches)], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 21, Folder 192)
    - [Melody, organ] 1903 Feb 4 (Box 21, Folder 193)
      - [Melody, organ] 1903 Feb 4, 3 p. of music; 35 cm.
      - [Melody, organ] 1903 Feb 4, 3 p. of music; 35 cm.
    - [Nineteen-twenty-nine, orchestra, op. 66, no. 1; arr.] "1929": a satire for orchestra. (Box 22, Folder 194)
      See also: A. Orchestral works. Nineteen twenty-nine, orchestra, op. 66, no. 1; and Tomorrow, orchestra, op. 66, no. 2.
      - [Nineteen-twenty-nine, orchestra, op. 66, no. 1; arr.] "1929": a satire for orchestra., 1 score (28 p.); 35 cm.
      - [Nineteen-twenty-nine, orchestra, op. 66, no. 1; arr.] "1929": a satire for orchestra., 1 score (29 p.); 35 cm.
    - Nocturne, piano.
    - "Olympian" two-step.
    - [Partita classica, organ, op. 70, no. 2] Studies in strict forms: ... No. 2. Partita classica. 1934 Jan 2, 11 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 195)
      Contents: I. Prelude and Fugue -- II. Passepied -- III. Air -- IV. Gigue.
      See also: Ground bass and fugue, organ, op. 70, no. 1; and Poem, organ, op. 70, no. 3.
    - [Piano piece] 1919 Apr 6, [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 196)
    - Piece, piano.
    - [Pièce grotesque] Pièce grotesque: or (thoughts of a gargoyle or some such title.) 1919 Apr 6, 3 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 197)
      Loose sheet laid in.
    - [Poem, organ, op. 70, no. 3] 1934-1949, 6 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 22, Folder 198)